Guide to the Office of Telecommunications records, 1896-2003 RG0067
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of Telecommunications records
1896-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Telecommunications
RG0067
18.25 Linear Feet
Collection contains campus directories (including telephone) of students and faculty, system design reports, needs assessments, contracts, correspondence.
Restrictions on Access
Series 2 and 3 are closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from Office of Telecommunications.
Historical or Biographical Note
Telecommunications Services is dedicated to providing state of the art telecommunications to support the voice, data and video needs of students, faculty, and staff of The George Washington University.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection contain campus directories (including telephone) of students and faculty, system design reports, needs assessments, contracts, correspondence, 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue and other office files, proposals, installation acceptances. The collections cover the years 1896-2003. Note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: four Departmental files, and Campus directories and telephone books
Washington (D.C.); Telephone systems; Contracts; Employees; Students; Directories; George Washington University; 2000 Pennsylvania Avenue (Washington, D.C.)
- Departmental files, 1960 ca.-1990; RG0067 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains brochures, instructions, a study, memorandums, news releases, publications, and a certificate. They range in date from approximately 1960 to 1990. The materials concern C&P Telephone Company, GW (George Washington University) Telecommunications Systems Department, dialing information, Centrex, tips for answering the phone, private branch exchange (PBX), local area networks (LAN), AT&T ACUS Service, the Center for Telecommunications Studies, telecommunication policy, committees, "Digital Bits: in telecommunications", and lectures.
  - Center for Telecommuncation Studies, 10/10/1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Departmental files, 1983-1987; RG0067 Series 2; 6 Linear feet
  This series contains contracts, correspondence, and 2000 Pennylvania (2000 Penn) Avenue records. This material covers the dates 1983-87.
- Departmental files, 1983-1990; RG0067 Series 3; 7.5 Linear feet
  This series contains proposals, and installation acceptances. The material covers the dates 1983-90.
- Departmental files, 1983-1990; RG0067 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series includes system design reports, and needs assessments. The material covers the dates 1983-90.
- Campus directories and telephone books, 1896-2003; RG0067 Series 5; 2.5 Linear feet (Box 1, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3, Box 2, Box 6)
  This series includes campus directories and telephone books. The material covers the dates 1896-2003.
  - Directory of the Columbian University, 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    2 copies
  - Social Register of George Washington University, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Telephone Directory, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    3 copies
  - Directory of Administrative and Instructional Staff, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Directory, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    2 volumes
  - Directory, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Directory, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Directory, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Directory, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Directory, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Telephone Directory, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Campus Directory, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Campus Directory, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Campus Directory, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Campus Directory, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Campus Directory, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Campus Directory, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Telephone Directory, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Campus Directory, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Campus Directory, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Campus Directory, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Campus Directory, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Telephone Directory, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    George Washington University Medical Center
  - Campus Directory, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Campus Directory, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - GWU Campus Directory, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - GWU Campus Directory, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Campus Directory, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - GWU Campus Directory, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - GWU Campus Directory, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Campus Directory, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Campus Directory, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Campus Directory, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Campus Directory, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Campus Directory, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Telephone Directory, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Telephone Directory, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Telephone Directory, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Phone Book, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Phone Book, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Telephone Directory, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Telephone Directory, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Telephone Directory, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Telephone Directory, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Telephone Directory, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Communications Directory, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Communications Directory, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Communications Directory, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Communications Directory, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Communications Directory, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Communications Directory, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Communication Directory, 2006; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Communication Directory, 2007; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Campus Directory, 1972-1984; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Directory of Faculty and Associates, 1987-1988; Series 5 (Box 6, Folder 4)